<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Michael J. Nicholson - Posts from 2022 on Michael J. Nicholson</title><link>https://michjnich.github.io/posts/tech/2022/</link><description>Recent content in Michael J. Nicholson - Posts from 2022 on Michael J. Nicholson</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 09:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://michjnich.github.io/posts/tech/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Debugging Django in a Docker container</title><link>https://michjnich.github.io/posts/tech/2022/2022_09_17_debug_django_in_docker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://michjnich.github.io/posts/tech/2022/2022_09_17_debug_django_in_docker/</guid><description>Have you ever tried hunting for a bug in a Django app that&amp;rsquo;s running in a Docker container? It&amp;rsquo;s not always a trivial process and can have you dotting print statements all over the place because you can&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to use breakpoints properly inside the Docker container.
Well, fortunately there is a solution to this. 2 solutions even.
Solution 1: Configure VS Code to debug a dockerised app Step 1 - Configure VS Code VS Code has built in debugging support for a variety of languages.</description></item><item><title>Power-up your DuckDuckGo searches with !bangs</title><link>https://michjnich.github.io/posts/tech/2022/2022_04_06_duckduckgo_bangs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://michjnich.github.io/posts/tech/2022/2022_04_06_duckduckgo_bangs/</guid><description>DuckDuckGo continues to gain ground over Google for searches, not least because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t track you. But is it as efficient as Google, and how can you get more out of it? Here are 5 simple tips:
Make use of !bangs DuckDuckGo has had bangs for years, though I only discovered them recently. Put simply, a bang allows you to perform a search directly on another site, from the DuckDuckGo site.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to v2 of michjnich.com</title><link>https://michjnich.github.io/posts/tech/2022/2022_04_03_welcome_to_v2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://michjnich.github.io/posts/tech/2022/2022_04_03_welcome_to_v2/</guid><description>Welcome &amp;hellip; &amp;hellip; to v2 of my personal site.
Version 1 was created using mkdocs and deployed on GitHub pages. Mkdocs is extremely simple to use and a powerful tool, but perhaps not ideal for a more &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo; looking site. While I could have run a blog using mkdocs, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely practical, and it was for that reason I then set up a seperate tech blog site.
stddev.tech This was actually pretty short lived, mainly because I used the hosted version of Ghost, which was quite expensive for somebody just running a small blog with only a handful of visitors, so when it came time to renew I found it hard to justify.</description></item></channel></rss>